Finding Aid for the Alex North Motion Picture Music PASC-M.0017
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alex North motion picture music
1951-1969
UCLA Library Special Collections
North, Alex
PASC-M.0017
41.5 Linear Feet (83 boxes.)
This collection consists of holograph scores with occasional holograph music notes
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Alex North; gift; 1976.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942335093606533
Biography
North was born on Dec. 4, 1910, in Chester, PA; attended the Curtis Institute, Juilliard School, and Moscow Conservatory; became music director of the German Theater Group and the Latvian State Theater, and the only American member of the Union of Soviet Composers; returned to the US in 1935; studied with Ernst Toch and Aaron Copland in NY, and composed ballet scores for Martha Graham, Hanya Holm, and Agnes de Mille; composed for the NY stage, including scores for Life and death of an American (1939), Of V we sing (1942), and Death of a salesman (1949); wrote music for some 50 documentary shorts between 1937-50; in 1939 went to Mexico as music director for the Anna Sokolow dance troupe and studied with Silvestre Revueltas; served as a captain in the US Army in World War II; his Revue for clarinet and orchestra was performed by Benny Goodman and the NY Philharmonic under Leonard Bernstein in 1946; began scoring feature films in the early 1950s, becoming a leading Hollywood composer; his musical language encompasses dissonance and lyricism, and ranges from chamber to symphonic proportions; he was nominated for 15 Academy Awards but did not win one until 1986, when the Motion Picture Academy presented him with an honorary life-achievement award; died in 1991.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of Alex North's holograph scores, with occasional holograph music notes, for the following motion pictures: The agony and the ecstasy (1965), All fall down (1962), The bachelor party (1957), The bad seed (1956), Cheyenne autumn (1964), The children's hour (1962), Cinerama South Seas adventure (1958), Cleopatra (1963), Death of a salesman (1951), Desiree (1954), Devil's brigade (1968), A dream of kings (1969), Go man go (1954), Hard contract (1969), Hot spell (1958), I'll cry tomorrow (1955), The king & four queens (1956), The long hot summer (1958), Man with the gun (1955), A member of the wedding (1953), Les miserables (1952), The misfits (1961), The outrage (1964), Pony soldier (1952), The racers (1955), The rainmaker (1956), The rose tattoo (1955), Sanctuary (1961), Shoes of the fisherman (1968), Spartacus (1960), Stagestruck (1958), A streetcar named Desire (1955), The thirteenth letter (1951), Unchained (1955), Viva Zapata (1952), Who's afraid of Virginia Woolf (1966), The wonderful country (1959), 2001, a space odyssey (1968), Symphony to a new continent, and Somebody killed her husband (1978).
Music -- Manuscripts.; Composers -- United States -- Archives.; Motion picture music -- Scores.; North, Alex -- Archives
- The Agony and the Ecstasy [20th Century-Fox, 1965]
  - North, Alex. (148 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score]. Cue Reel/Part, Title, Leaves (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Main title, 6 [1-6] (Othertype 1 1)
    - Enemy-distance; Pope's army, 15 [7-21] (Othertype 1 2)
    - Marble: sketch #1, 3 [22-24] (Othertype 1 3)
    - 12 Apostles: sketch #1, 4 [27-30] (Othertype 3 1)
    - 12 Apostles, 3 [31=33] (Othertype 3 1)
    - Apostle's Sketch [rough], 6 [34-39] (Othertype 4 3, Othertype 5 1)
    - Apostle's sketch, 4 [40-43] (Othertype 4 3, Othertype 5 1)
    - Sketch destroyed [rough], 1 [44] (Othertype 5 4)
    - Sketch destroyed, 1 [45] (Othertype 5 4)
    - Refuge [rough], 2 [46-47] (Othertype 6 4, Othertype 7 1)
    - Refuge, 2 [48-49] (Othertype 6 4, Othertype 7 1)
    - Genesis [rough], 6 [50-55] (Othertype 7 2)
    - Genesis, 6 [56-61] (Othertype 7 2)
    - [Battlefield scene], 19 [62-80] (Othertype 7 3)
    - The Sistine Chapel, 5 [81-85] (Othertype 7 4, Othertype 8 1)
    - Painting [rough], 4 [86-89] (Othertype 8 4, Othertype 9 1, Othertype 9 2)
    - Painting, 4 [90-93] (Othertype 8 4, Othertype 9 1, Othertype 9 2)
    - St. Peter's, 1 [94] (Othertype 9 3)
    - Blind, 7 [95-101] (Othertype 10 1)
    - Festivity, 11 [102-112] (Othertype 10 2)
    - Original sketch not returned [no music], 1 [113] (Othertype 11 1)
    - Recruiting, 11 [114-124] (Othertype 11 3, Othertype 12 1)
    - To battle, 8 [125-132] (Othertype 12 2)
    - Defeat, 10 [133-142] (Othertype 13 1)
    - Julius, 4 [143-146] (Othertype 14 1)
    - End title cast, 2 [147-148] (Othertype 16 4)
- All Fall Down [MGM, 1962]
  - North,Alex. (60 leaves) [Cue chart with titles, timings, orchestrations, and notes] - 1 leaf, (back of blank score), pencil. [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score]. (Box Unknown container 252 for instance of North,Alex. (60 leaves) [Cue chart with titles, timings, orchestrations, and notes] - 1 leaf, (back of blank score), pencil. [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score]., Folder 2)
    - Main title, 6 [1-6] (Othertype 1 1)
    - Bridge #1, 1 [7] (Othertype 2 1)
    - Bridge #2, 1 [8] (Othertype 2 2)
    - Bridge #3, 1 [9] (Othertype 2 3)
    - So long, 2 [10-11] (Othertype 2 6)
    - Diary, 1 [12] (Othertype 3 2)
    - Diary #1 (new), 1 [13] (Othertype 3 2)
    - You just feel it, 1 [14] (Othertype 4 3)
    - You just feel it/new revised, ] [15] (Othertype 4 3)
    - You're my guy, 1 [16] (Othertype 4 4, Othertype 5 A1)
    - The past, 3 [17-19] (Othertype 5 3)
    - Still my guy, 1 [20] (Othertype 5 4, Othertype 6 1)
    - Alone, 3 [21-23] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Spring, 1 [24] (Othertype 7 2)
    - Hate life, 2 [25-26] (Othertype 8 1)
    - Take it easy, 2 [27-28] (Othertype 8 3)
    - Conflict, 3 [29-31] (Othertype 9 2)
    - Goes double, 2 [32-33] (Othertype 9 5, Othertype 10 1, Othertype 10 2)
    - Trouble, 1 [34] (Othertype 10 4)
    - Shut up, 9 [35-43] (Othertype 10 5)
    - Pregnant, 3 [44-46] (Othertype 11 1)
    - Decision, 6 [47-52] (Othertype 11 2)
    - Revenge, 2 [53-54] (Othertype 12 1A)
    - E.[nd] T.[itle], 6 [55-60] (Othertype 12 2)
- American Road
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 46, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 48, Folder unknown container)
- The Bachelor Party [United Artists, 1957]
  - North, Alex. (62 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Theme from the Bachelor Party, 9 [1-9] (Othertype ________)
    - Lookin' for laughs (theme); melody only w/ words, 3 [10-12] (Othertype ________)
    - M[ain] T[itle] [piano short score], 6 [13-18] (Othertype ________)
    - [ditto; ozalid copy on recto and verso pages], 3 [19-21] (Othertype ________)
    - [ditto; ozalid copy with timings marked in red pencil], 3 [22-24] (Othertype ________)
    - Main title [full score], 11 [25-35] (Othertype ________)
    - [no title], 14 [36-49] (Othertype 7 1, Othertype 8 1)
    - End title [piano? score], 4 [50-53] (Othertype ________)
    - End title [full? score], 9 [54-62] (Othertype ________)
- The Bad Seed [Warner Brothers, 1956]
  - North, Alex. (131 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Main title, 10 [1-10] (Othertype 1 1)
    - The dream, 5 [11-15] (Othertype 1 2)
    - The locket, 1 (folded: 4 pp.) [16] (Othertype 2 1)
    - Swall me a frog, 2 [17-18] (Othertype 2 2)
    - Transition, 2 [19-20] (Othertype 3 1)
    - Basket of kisses, 3 (folded) [21-23] (Othertype 4 2)
    - Fairy late, 2 [24-25] (Othertype 4 3)
    - Concern, 2 [26-27] (Othertype 5 1)
    - Kenneth, 3 [28-30] (Othertype 5 2)
    - No more children, 5 [31-35] (Othertype 6 2)
    - The medal, 1 [36] (Othertype 6 3)
    - Truth, 4 [37-40] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Insert, 2 [41-42] (Othertype 7 1A)
    - It isn't true, 3 [43-45] (Othertype 7 2)
    - Probing, 6 [46-51] (Othertype 8 1)
    - Test, 5 [52-56] (Othertype 8 2)
    - Identity, 6 [57-62] (Othertype 9 1, Othertype 10 1)
    - Confession, 5 [63-67] (Othertype 10 2)
    - Details, 9 [68-76] (Othertype 11 1)
    - Princess, 6 [77-82] (Othertype 11 2)
    - Our baby, 5 [83-87] (Othertype 12 2)
    - My baby, 11 [88-98] (Othertype 13 1)
    - Sleep well, 5 [99-103] (Othertype 14 1)
    - Daddy, 3 [104-106] (Othertype 14 2)
    - At it again, 7 [107-113] (Othertype 15 1)
    - [no title], 3 [114-116] (Othertype 15 1A)
    - [no title], 3 [117-119] (Othertype 15 2)
    - The final bang, 4 (folded) + 1 [120-124] (Othertype 15 3)
    - End cast, 4 [125-128] (Othertype 15 4)
    - Bad Seed theme, [UNK] [129-131] (Othertype ________)
- Bullet
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 29, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Manuscripts and parts. (Box 30, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 31, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 32, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 36, Folder unknown container)
- Cheyenne Autumn [Warner Brothers, 1964]
  - North, Alex. (164 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Main title, 4 [1-4] (Othertype ________)
    - Hope, 2 [5-6] (Othertype 1 4)
    - unspecified (Othertype 2 1)
    - Friend Deborah, 3 [7-9] (Othertype 2 2)
    - Waiting, 6 [10-15] (Othertype 2 3, Othertype 2 4, Othertype 3 1)
    - Truth, 1 [16] (Othertype 3 1A)
    - Proposal, 2 [17-18] (Othertype 3 2)
    - Going home, 2 [19-20] (Othertype 4 2)
    - Dedication, 2 [21-22] (Othertype 4 3)
    - Trek going home theme, 2 [23-24] (Othertype 4 4)
    - Calvary [sic], 1 [25] (Othertype 4 5)
    - Archer, 4 [26-29] (Othertype [4] 5A)
    - War, 3 [30-32] (Othertype 5 1)
    - Fire, 9 [33-41] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Old Chief, 2 [42-43] (Othertype 6 2)
    - Tall Tree's Death, 1 [44] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Mourning, 1 [45] (Othertype 7 3)
    - Montage, 10 [46-55] (Othertype 7 4)
    - God help me, 1 [56] (Othertype 7 5, Othertype 8 1)
    - Preparation to battle, 5 [57-61] (Othertype 8 2)
    - Battle, 17 [62-78] (Othertype 8 3)
    - [no title], 6 [79-84] (Othertype 9 1)
    - Red shirt, 2 [85-86] (Othertype 9 1A)
    - Cattle drive, 4 [87-90] (Othertype 9 2)
    - Sick girl, 1 (frag) and 4 [91-95 (Othertype 9 3)
    - Buffalo, 9 [96-]04] (Othertype 9 4, Othertype 10 1)
    - [no title], 1 [105] (Othertype 12 4A)
    - Intermission, 1 [106] (Othertype _____)
    - Low bridge, 4 [107-110] (Othertype 13 3, Othertype 14 1)
    - Deborah's book [melody only], 1[111] (Othertype 14 2)
    - [ditto? ozalid copy], 1 [112] (Othertype 14 2)
    - Transitions, 6 [113-118] (Othertype 14 3)
    - Lead our people home, 5 [119-123] (Othertype 14 4)
    - Lead our people home (cont'd), 7 [124-130] (Othertype 15 1)
    - Revolt, 3 [131-133] (Othertype 16 1)
    - Departure, 2 [134-135] (Othertype 17 1)
    - The people, 2 [136-137] (Othertype 17 2, Othertype 18 1)
    - [no title], 5 [138-142] (Othertype 18 3)
    - [no title], 5 [143-147] (Othertype 19 1)
    - Spring, 7 [148-154] (Othertype 19 2)
    - Home, 3 [155-157] (Othertype 20 1)
    - The end, 5 [158-162] (Othertype 20 3)
    - End cast, 2 [163-164] (Othertype 20 4)
- The Children's Hour [United Artists, 1962]
  - North, Alex. [Timing sheets] Reel 10 cue 10/2: caress. - 2 leaves typescript. [Cue chart with titles, orchestrations, and notes]. 1 leaf, pencil. [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score - 57 leaves]. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Proposal, 7 [1-7] (Othertype 2 2)
    - Shame, 3 [8-10] (Othertype 3 1)
    - [ditto: ozalid copy], 3 [11-13] (Othertype 3 1)
    - Mary's lie, 5 [14-18] (Othertype 3 2)
    - Tantrum, 4 [19-22] (Othertype 4 1)
    - [no title], 1 [23] (Othertype 5 1)
    - [no title], 5 [24-28] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Results, 2 [29-30] (Othertype 6 3)
    - Confession, 1 [31] (Othertype 9 1)
    - Alone, 7 [32-38] (Othertype 9 2, Othertype 10 1)
    - Caress, 3 [2nd frag.; 3rd doubled] [39-41] (Othertype 10 2)
    - Shock, 2 [42-43] (Othertype 12 1)
    - Realization, 8 [4th=frag) [44-51] (Othertype 13 1)
    - Peace, 4 [52-55] (Othertype 14 1)
    - End title, 2 [56-57] (Othertype 14 2)
- Cinerama: South Seas Adventure [Cinerama, 1958]
  - North, Alex. (160 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score]. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Cinerama South Seas, 9 [1-9] (Othertype 1 1)
    - Ula no weo, 4 [10-13] (Othertype 1 2)
    - Ted & Kay, 3 [14-16] (Othertype 1 3)
    - First surf riding, 6 [17-22] (Othertype 1 4)
    - Hawaii by air, 6 [23-28] (Othertype 1 5)
    - Fashion show, 3 [29-31] (Othertype 2 1)
    - Sailing at Waikiki, 2 [32-33] (Othertype 2 2)
    - Start of Tavaga's voyage, 9 [34-42] (Othertype 2 3)
    - King Neptune, 4 [43-46] (Othertype 2 5)
    - T[a]vaga reaches Tahiti, 2 [47-48] (Othertype 3 1)
    - Gauguin, 3 [49-51] (Othertype 3 2)
    - Spear contest, 2 [52-53] (Othertype 3 3)
    - Farewell to Tahiti, 2 [54-55] (Othertype 3 4)
    - Trip to Tonga, 5 [56-60] (Othertype 4 1)
    - Fiji, 4 [61-64] (Othertype 5 1)
    - Sailing to the New Hebrides, 2 [65-66] (Othertype 5 2)
    - Head-diver sequence, 6 [67-72] (Othertype 5 3)
    - End of Act I, 1 [73] (Othertype 5 4)
    - Ski life, 8 [74-81] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Driving thru New Zealand, 8 [82-89] (Othertype 6 2)
    - Flying over New Zealand, 13 [90-102] (Othertype 6 3)
    - Australia. Bluey Brink: Bush song., 8 [103-110] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Zoo, 5 [111-115] (Othertype 7 2)
    - Luna Park, 7 [116-122] (Othertype 7 3)
    - Bondi Beach, 3 [123-125] (Othertype 7 4)
    - Brisbaine, 6 [126-131] (Othertype 7 5)
    - Welcome, 3 [132-134] (Othertype 7 6)
    - Sheep shearing, 7 [135-141] (Othertype 8 1-1A)
    - Kangaroo round-up, 7 [142-148] (Othertype 8 2)
    - [no title], 5 [145-153] (Othertype 8 2A)
    - Bobby Koscheck, ] [154] (Othertype 8 3)
    - Farewell to Australia, 3 [155-157] (Othertype 9 4)
    - Finale, 3 [158-160] (Othertype 9 5)
- Cleopatra [20th Century-Fox, 1963]
  - North, Alex. (328 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - Pharsalia, 2 [1-2] (Othertype 1 2)
    - Caesar to Egypt, 1 [3] (Othertype 1 3)
    - Alexandria, 1 [4] (Othertype 2 2)
    - 12 Egyptian trumpets, 1 [5] (Othertype 2 3)
    - King Ptolymy [sic?], 1 [6] (Othertype 2 5)
    - Pompeii's ring [rough], 2 [7-8] (Othertype 2 8, Othertype 3 1)
    - Caesar's Theme (Pompoi's [sic] ring), 5 [9-13] (Othertype 2 8, Othertype 3 1)
    - Cleo's entrance, 2 [14-15] (Othertype 3 2)
    - Only yesterday, 2 [16-17] (Othertype 4 1)
    - Epilespse [sic], 4[18-21] (Othertype 4 2)
    - Blind poet, 1 [22] (Othertype 4 2B)
    - [Blind poet] Revised final, Dec. 17, 1962; 1 [23] (Othertype 4 2B)
    - Blind poet #2, 2 [24-25] (Othertype 4 3)
    - [Blind poet #2] Revised final, Dec 17 1962; 2 [26-27] (Othertype 4 3)
    - Pastime, 3 [28-30] (Othertype 5 1)
    - [Pastime] Final Revised, Dec. 17, 1962; 2 [31-32] (Othertype 5 1)
    - The great library [rough], 5 [33-37] (Othertype 5 2)
    - Great library, 3 [38-40] (Othertype 5 2)
    - Moongate, 26 [41-66] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Lotus, 2 [67-68] (Othertype 6 2, Othertype 7 1)
    - Sympathy, 2 [69-70] (Othertype 7 2)
    - Fertility, 10[71-80] (Othertype 8 2)
    - Cleos quarters (new), 4 [81-84] (Othertype 8 2)
    - Alexander's tomb, 8 [85-92] (Othertype 8 3)
    - Calpurnia, 3 [93-95] (Othertype 9 1)
    - Son of Isis, 6 [96-101] (Othertype 9 2)
    - Son of Caesar, 6 [102-107] (Othertype 9 3, Othertype 10 1)
    - Caesar's departure, 6 [108-113] (Othertype 10 2)
    - Horseman s fanfare, 2 [114-115] (Othertype 11 1)
    - Archers, 2 [116-117] (Othertype 11 2)
    - African dancers #1, 4 [118-121] (Othertype 11 3)
    - African dance revised final, Dec 17, 1962; 3 [122-124] (Othertype 11 3)
    - African Dancers #2, 3 [125-127] (Othertype 11 4)
    - Copa girls, 4 [128-131] (Othertype 11 5)
    - [Processional fanfare] Revised final, Dec 17 1962; 1 [134] (Othertype 11 6)
    - Processional, 9 [135-143] (Othertype 11 7)
    - unspecified (Othertype 12 1)
    - By divine right, 3 [144-146] (Othertype 12 3, Othertype 13 1)
    - Warhing, 2 [147-148] (Othertype 13 2)
    - Premonition, 2 [149-150] (Othertype 14 1)
    - Assasination, 8 [151-158] (Othertype 14 1A)
    - Requiem, 4 [159-162] (Othertype 14 2)
    - Requiem revised final, Dec 13 1963; 1 [163] (Othertype 14 2)
    - [no title], 8 [164-171] (Othertype 16 1)
    - Isis, 4 [172-175] (Othertype 17 1)
    - The Nile, 9 [176-184] (Othertype 17 3)
    - Most becoming, 2 [185-186] (Othertype 18 3A)
    - Food Repast, 4 [187-190] (Othertype 18 5)
    - Anthony-Cleo in [UNK], 5 [191-195] (Othertype 18 6, Othertype 18 7, Othertype 19 1)
    - Bacchus, 16 [196-211] (Othertype 19 2)
    - Bacchus insert, 1 [212] (Othertype 19 2A)
    - [ditto: ozalid copy], 1 [213] (Othertype 19 2A)
    - Anthony-Cleo's love, 6 [214-219] (Othertype 19 3, Othertype 19 4)
    - One breath closer, 5 [220-224] (Othertype 20 1)
    - Thwarted, 3 [225-227] (Othertype 21 1)
    - Athens, 4 [228-231] (Othertype 21 2, Othertype 22 1)
    - Cleo's ambition, 2 [232-233] (Othertype 23 1)
    - War, 2 [234-235] (Othertype 24 1)
    - Interlude, 2 [236-237] (Othertype 24 2)
    - Bre-sea battle, 8 [238-245] (Othertype 24 3, Othertype 25 1)
    - Hope, 8 [246-253] (Othertype 25 1A)
    - Doomed, 9 [254-262] (Othertype 25 3, Othertype 26 1)
    - [no title], 13 [263-275] (Othertype 26 2)
    - Defeat, 1 [276] (Othertype 27 1, Othertype 27 2)
    - Defeat/they told me you were dead, 5 [277-281] (Othertype 27 1, Othertype 27 2)
    - Two heads, 1 [282] (Othertype 27 3)
    - Better late than never, 5 [283-287] (Othertype 28 1)
    - Cleo's son leaves, 2 [288-289] (Othertype 29 2)
    - Anthony's camp, 2 [290-291] (Othertype 29 3)
    - Never fear, 4 [292-295] (Othertype 29 4, Othertype 30 1)
    - Denoument [sic], 5 [296-300] (Othertype 30 2)
    - Anthony's retreat, 1 [301] (Othertype 30 3)
    - Transitions, 3 [302-304] (Othertype 30 X, Othertype 31 1)
    - Anthony's death, 9 [305-313] (Othertype 31 2)
    - Remorse, 5 [314-318] (Othertype 32 1)
    - Cleo's death, 5 [319-323] (Othertype 32 2, Othertype 31 1)
    - Epilogue, 5 [324-328] (Othertype 32 2)
- Death of a Salesman [Columbia, 1951]
  - North, Alex. [Notes] - 1 leaf (legal paper), pencil. [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score (90 leaves)] (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Main title, 7 [1-7] (Othertype 1 A)
    - Windshield, 2 [8-9] (Othertype 2 A)
    - Polishing car, 7 [10-16] (Othertype 3 A)
    - Boston girl, 6 [17-22] (Othertype 3 B)
    - Casino game, 4 [23-26] (Othertype 4 A)
    - Boys meet Ben, 4 [27-30] (Othertype 4 B)
    - Rubber pipe, 5 [31-35] (Othertype 5 A)
    - Willy fired, 4 [36-39] (Othertype 7 B)
    - Subway, 1 [40] (Othertype 7 C)
    - Biff the champ, 2 [41-42] (Othertype 8 A)
    - Biff the champ (alternate), 1 [43] (Othertype 8 A)
    - Stolen pen [rough], 2 [44-45] (Othertype 10 A)
    - Stolen pen, 2 [46-47] (Othertype 10 A-B-C-D)
    - Boston again, 2 [48-49] (Othertype 10 C)
    - Willie plants, 8 [50-57] (Othertype 11 A)
    - Willie decides, 4 [58-61] (Othertype 12 A)
    - Death Ride, 3 [62-64] (Othertype 12 B)
    - Death ride cont'd, 5 [65-69] (Othertype 12 B)
    - Goodbye Willie, 6 [70-75] (Othertype 12 C)
    - Boston girl [full score], 15 [76-90] (Box-folder 4/11, Othertype 3 B)
- Desiree [20th Century-Fox, 1954]
  - North, Alex. (78 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Adolescence, 2 [1-2] (Othertype 1 1A)
    - Youthful Diary #1, 3 [3-5] (Othertype 2 2)
    - [no title], 2 [6-7] (Othertype 2 3)
    - Proposal, 6 [8-13] (Othertype 2 4)
    - Paris, 1 [14] (Othertype 3 3)
    - Unrequited, 5 [15-19] (Othertype 3 6)
    - Cradle Berceuse, 7 [20-26] (Othertype 3 7)
    - Reflections, 2 [27-28] (Othertype 4 1)
    - Wooed, 5 [29-33], with fragment [3A] orig. taped to [31] (Othertype 5 2)
    - Conflict, 2 [34-35] (Othertype 5 3)
    - Piqued, 5 [36-40] (Othertype 6 2)
    - Proclamation Desertion, 6 [41-46] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Offer, 3 [47-49] (Folder 7 3, Folder 8 1)
    - Etiquette, 6 [50-55] (Folder 8 2, Folder 9 1)
    - [no title-incomplete], 2 [56-57] (Folder _____)
    - [no title], 5 [58-62] (Folder 10 3)
    - Transition, 4 [63-66] (Folder 11 1)
    - Decision, 2 [67-68] (Folder 11 2)
    - [no title], 5 [69-73] (Folder 11 3, Folder 12 1)
    - Farewell, 2 [74-75] (Folder 12 2)
    - Farewell: this version Marseillaise starts after Des. leaves N. completely alone., 2 [76-77] (Folder 12 2X)
    - Decision conductor comp., 1, folded (2 pp) (Folder _____)
    - Alex North Orch. Maurice de Packh, [78]
- Devil's Brigade [United Artists, 1968]
  - North, Alex. (91 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Tease, 3 [1-3] (Othertype 1 1A)
    - German Captain, 1 [4] (Othertype 1 3)
    - Vixen, 4 [5-8] (Othertype 1 6)
    - Moffatt, 3 [9-11] (Othertype 2 1)
    - Friends, 4 [12-15] (Othertype 2 4, Othertype 3 1)
    - Hike pt. 1, 5 [16-20] (Othertype 4 1)
    - Hike pt. 2, 13 [21-33] (Othertype 5 1)
    - Dunkirke Speech, 2 [34-35] (Othertype 5 2)
    - Skiing, 5 [36-40] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Parade march, 4 [41-44] (Othertype 8 1)
    - The Stream, 6 [45-50] (Othertype 10 1)
    - Stream continued, 1 [51] (Othertype 10 2)
    - Infliltrating the city, 6 [52-57] (Othertype 10 4)
    - Gathering of Prisoners, 10 [58-67] (Othertype 10 5)
    - [no title], 7 [68-74] (Othertype 11 2)
    - Santa Elia wrap-up, 5 [75-79] (Othertype 11 4)
    - Crown's speech, 1 [80] (Othertype 12 2)
    - Climb up the mountain, 3 [81-83] (Othertype 13 1)
    - Continue climb, 8[84-91] (Othertype 13 2)
- A Dream of Kings [National General Corp., 1969]
  - North, Alex. [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score (95 leaves)] Cue chart with titles, times, and orchestration notes (1 leaf). (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
    - Main title, 5 [1-5] (Othertype 1 A)
    - [Main title] alternate [to page 4], 1 [6] (Othertype [1 A])
    - M[ain] T[itle] [alternate to bars 24-26], 1 [7] (Othertype [1 A])
    - M[ain] T[itle] [sketches], 8 [8-15] (Othertype [1 A])
    - M[ain] T[itle] E[nd] T[itle] [sketch], 1 [16] (Othertype [1 A])
    - [Main title?] [sketch], 3 [17-19] (Othertype [1 A])
    - Anna, 3 [20-22] (Othertype 1 1)
    - Anna [sketch], 2 [23-24] (Othertype 1 1)
    - To precede King again--2-1, 1 [25] (Othertype ______)
    - King again, 7 [26-32] (Othertype 2 1)
    - King again [sketches], 7 [33-39] (Othertype 2 1)
    - Slight despair, 2 [40-41] (Othertype 2 3)
    - Slight despair (sketch), 2 [42-43] (Othertype 2 3)
    - A Winner, 3 [44-46] (Othertype 3 1)
    - A winner (sketch), 2 [47-50] (Othertype 3 1)
    - Rejuvenated, 1 [51] (Othertype 3 1)
    - Sunshine of Greece, 7 [52-58] (Othertype 4 1, Othertype 5 1)
    - Sunshine of Greece [alternate?], 2 [59-60] (Othertype 4 1)
    - [Sunshine of Greece, sketches], 12 [61-72] (Othertype 4 1)
    - To church, 1 [73] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Cicero, 4 [74-77] (Othertype 8 1)
    - Cicero [sketches], 2 [78-79] (Othertype 8 1)
    - Mt. Olympus, 1 [80] (Othertype 8 2)
    - Hope, 4 [81-84] (Othertype 12 1)
    - Hope [sketches], 3 [85-87] (Othertype 12 1)
    - End Title, 1 [88] (Othertype 12 2)
    - End cast, 2 [89-90] (Othertype 12 3)
    - End Cast [sketch], 1 [91] (Othertype [12 2])
    - Dream of Kings [cue sheet with columns for reel and part, title, time, and orchestration notes], 1 [92] (Box-folder 4/15, Othertype ______)
    - Desparate, 4 [93-96] (Othertype 10 1)
- F.D.R. Series
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 55, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 56, Folder unknown container)
- Go Man Go [United Artists, 1954]